<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Decomposition on Tan Zhou</title>
    <link>/tags/decomposition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Decomposition on Tan Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/decomposition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian decomposition of full waveform LiDAR data with uncertainty analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/bayesian_decomposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/bayesian_decomposition/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
A thorough understanding of full waveform (FW) LiDAR data processing and associated uncertainty is critical to vegetation applications such as retrieving forest structure variables and estimating forest biomass.
Goal:
To qunaitfy the uncertaitny of the estimation and gain a deep understanding of waveform lidar processing.
Methods:
This paper applies the Bayesian non-linear modeling concept to process small-footprint FW LiDAR data (the Bayesian decomposition) collected at a study site of the National Ecological Observatory Network (NEON) to investigate its potential for waveform decomposition and uncertainty estimation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold-A novel deconvolution algorithm with optimization for waveform LiDAR processing</title>
      <link>/publications/gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/gold/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Waveform Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data have advantages over discrete-return LiDAR data inaccurately characterizing vegetation structure. However, we lack a comprehensive understanding ofwaveform data processing approaches under different topography and vegetation conditions.
Goal:
The objec-tive of this paper is to highlight a novel deconvolution algorithm, the Gold algorithm, for processingwaveform LiDAR data with optimal deconvolution parameters. Further, we present a comparative studyof waveform processing methods to provide insight into selecting an approach for a given combination ofvegetation and terrain characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>