<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Waveformlidar on Tan Zhou</title>
    <link>/tags/waveformlidar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Waveformlidar on Tan Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/waveformlidar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R package - waveformlidar data processing and analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/contributions/waveformlidar_r_package/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/contributions/waveformlidar_r_package/</guid>
      <description>Make waveform lidar processing become easier and enable users can use exisitng Discrete-return lidar data processing tools.
Introduction:
A wealth of Full Waveform (FW) LiDAR data are available to the public from different sources, which is poised to boost the extensive application of FW LiDAR data. However, we lack a handy and open source tool that can be used by potential users for processing and analyzing FW LiDAR data. To this end, we introduce waveformlidar, an R package dedicated to FW LiDAR processing, analysis and visualization as a solution to the constraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package - waveformlidar data processing and analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/waveformlidar_r_package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/waveformlidar_r_package/</guid>
      <description>Make waveform lidar processing become easier and enable users can use exisitng Discrete-return lidar data processing tools.
Introduction:
A wealth of Full Waveform (FW) LiDAR data are available to the public from different sources, which is poised to boost the extensive application of FW LiDAR data. However, we lack a handy and open source tool that can be used by potential users for processing and analyzing FW LiDAR data. To this end, we introduce waveformlidar, an R package dedicated to FW LiDAR processing, analysis and visualization as a solution to the constraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>waveform decomposition vs. deconvolution</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/waveformlidar_processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/waveformlidar_processing/</guid>
      <description>Goal:
Make waveform lidar processing become easier and enable users can use exisitng Discrete-return lidar data processing tools.
Introduction:
Waveform Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data have advantages over discrete-return LiDAR data in accurately characterizing vegetation structure. However, we lack a comprehensive understanding of waveform data processing approaches under different topography and vegetation conditions. The objective of this paper is to highlight a novel deconvolution algorithm, the Gold algorithm, for processing waveform LiDAR data with optimal deconvolution parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian decompostion of waveform lidar and uncertaitny analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/bayesian_decompostion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/bayesian_decompostion/</guid>
      <description>The subsquent section is mainly to show how to quantify the uncertaity of waveform processing uinsg Bayesian method. The detailed description of the approach can refer to https://www.researchgate.net/publication/319018940_Bayesian_decomposition_of_full_waveform_LiDAR_data_with_uncertainty_analysis
In the domain of LiDAR applications, the observations or data are inherently subject to various errors such as system setting, system calibration, and range measurement errors. Additionally, the LiDAR vendors often do not clearly state what errors are considered when the data are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>