<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine learning on Tan Zhou</title>
    <link>/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine learning on Tan Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentimental analysis of reviewers&#39; feedback using BERT vs. Machien learning</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/sentimental-analysis-of-reviewers-feedback-using-bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/sentimental-analysis-of-reviewers-feedback-using-bert/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Note: Retraining the BERT model took a long time using a local computer, to run in the Google Colab will be a good choice
Objectives To predict sentiment (postive, neutral, negeative) of customer feedback using tweet texts of differnt airline companies and compare different models&amp;rsquo;performace on text classification.
Specifically, multiple machine learing models such as KNN, Random forest and SVC have been used for conduct classification as a baseline. A new language representation model named BERT (Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers) was also implemented to conduct sentiment analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud detection using ML and PySpark framework</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/pyspark_ml_fraud_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/pyspark_ml_fraud_detection/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The image on the right was obtained from here.
There is a lack of public available datasets on financial services and specially in the emerging mobile money transactions domain. Financial datasets are important to many researchers and in particular to us performing research in the domain of fraud detection. Part of the problem is the intrinsically private nature of financial transactions, that leads to no publicly available datasets.
A synthetic dataset were generated using the simulator called PaySim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble models for classification (combine deep learning with machine learning)</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/ensemble_models_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/ensemble_models_classification/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Ensemble modeling is a process where multiple diverse models are created to predict an outcome, either by using many different modeling algorithms or using different training data sets. The ensemble model then aggregates the prediction of each base model and results in once final prediction for the unseen data. The motivation for using ensemble models is to reduce the generalization error of the prediction. As long as the base models are diverse and independent, the prediction error of the model decreases when the ensemble approach is used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>