<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deconvolution on Tan Zhou</title>
    <link>/tags/deconvolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deconvolution on Tan Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/deconvolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>waveformlidar: An R Package for Waveform LiDAR Processing and Analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/waveformlidar_r_package/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/waveformlidar_r_package/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
A wealth of FullWaveform (FW) LiDAR (Light Detection and Ranging) data are available to the public from different sources, which is poised to boost extensive applications of FW LiDAR data. However, we lack a handy and open source tool that can be used by potential users for processing and analyzing FW LiDAR data.
Goal: To this end, we introduce waveformlidar, an R package dedicated to FW LiDAR processing, analysis and visualization as a solution to the constraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold-A novel deconvolution algorithm with optimization for waveform LiDAR processing</title>
      <link>/publications/gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/gold/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Waveform Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data have advantages over discrete-return LiDAR data inaccurately characterizing vegetation structure. However, we lack a comprehensive understanding ofwaveform data processing approaches under different topography and vegetation conditions.
Goal:
The objec-tive of this paper is to highlight a novel deconvolution algorithm, the Gold algorithm, for processingwaveform LiDAR data with optimal deconvolution parameters. Further, we present a comparative studyof waveform processing methods to provide insight into selecting an approach for a given combination ofvegetation and terrain characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>