<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creations on Tan Zhou</title>
    <link>/projects/creations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creations on Tan Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/creations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Uncertainty for EVI prediction using LSTM and autoencoder</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/bayesian-uncertainty-of-neutral-networks-lstm-for-time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/bayesian-uncertainty-of-neutral-networks-lstm-for-time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Bayesian NN How much confidence do you know about your model results or a paritcular prediction?
This is a critical important question for many business. With the advent of deep learning, many forecasting problems for business have been solved in innovative ways. For example, Uber researchers has provided a fascianting paper on time series prediction.
Standard deep learning method such as LSTM do not capture model uncertianty. However, the uncertianty estimation is indispensable for deep learning models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis for review classification using SWIVEL and a small datasets</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/nlp_swivel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/nlp_swivel/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Genealy, it require an amount of data to train and a long time to train a NLP model for a specific dataset. Transfer learning is commonly used in this case to conduct the sentiment analsis for Natural Language Processing (NLP) problem.
Swivel performs approximate factorization of the point-wise mutual information matrix via stochastic gradient descent. It uses a piecewise loss with special handling for unobserved co-occurrences, and thus makes use of all the information in the matrix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble models for classification (combine deep learning with machine learning)</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/ensemble_models_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/ensemble_models_classification/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Ensemble modeling is a process where multiple diverse models are created to predict an outcome, either by using many different modeling algorithms or using different training data sets. The ensemble model then aggregates the prediction of each base model and results in once final prediction for the unseen data. The motivation for using ensemble models is to reduce the generalization error of the prediction. As long as the base models are diverse and independent, the prediction error of the model decreases when the ensemble approach is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian optimization deep learning</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/bayesian_optimziation_nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/bayesian_optimziation_nn/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
The picture of Bayesian optimization is obtianed from here
Bayesian optimization
There are a lot of hyperparameters for machine learning models such as NN. Typically, random or grid search are effecient ways to conduct the optimization of models. They can be very time-consuming in some cases which waste time on unpromising areas of search space. Bayesian optimization can overcome this problem by adopting an informed seach method in the space to find the optmized parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package - waveformlidar data processing and analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/waveformlidar_r_package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/waveformlidar_r_package/</guid>
      <description>Make waveform lidar processing become easier and enable users can use exisitng Discrete-return lidar data processing tools.
Introduction:
A wealth of Full Waveform (FW) LiDAR data are available to the public from different sources, which is poised to boost the extensive application of FW LiDAR data. However, we lack a handy and open source tool that can be used by potential users for processing and analyzing FW LiDAR data. To this end, we introduce waveformlidar, an R package dedicated to FW LiDAR processing, analysis and visualization as a solution to the constraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>waveform decomposition vs. deconvolution</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/waveformlidar_processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/waveformlidar_processing/</guid>
      <description>Goal:
Make waveform lidar processing become easier and enable users can use exisitng Discrete-return lidar data processing tools.
Introduction:
Waveform Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data have advantages over discrete-return LiDAR data in accurately characterizing vegetation structure. However, we lack a comprehensive understanding of waveform data processing approaches under different topography and vegetation conditions. The objective of this paper is to highlight a novel deconvolution algorithm, the Gold algorithm, for processing waveform LiDAR data with optimal deconvolution parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian decompostion of waveform lidar and uncertaitny analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/bayesian_decompostion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/bayesian_decompostion/</guid>
      <description>The subsquent section is mainly to show how to quantify the uncertaity of waveform processing uinsg Bayesian method. The detailed description of the approach can refer to https://www.researchgate.net/publication/319018940_Bayesian_decomposition_of_full_waveform_LiDAR_data_with_uncertainty_analysis
In the domain of LiDAR applications, the observations or data are inherently subject to various errors such as system setting, system calibration, and range measurement errors. Additionally, the LiDAR vendors often do not clearly state what errors are considered when the data are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree segmentation using free available tools</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/tree_segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/tree_segmentation/</guid>
      <description>BOSH (Bosh Outer SHell) &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;is an open source tool for release engineering, deployment, lifecycle management, and monitoring of distributed systems.&amp;rdquo; And it&amp;rsquo;s amazingly powerful. This examples uses BOSH to provision an Alassian vendor app running on JDK along with the support Postgres database and agents to support it. The releases manages the health of services and will automatically provision, start/stop processes across the various services.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>