<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Tan Zhou</title>
    <link>/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Tan Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Learning Semantic Segmentation-Based Approach for Field-Level Sorghum Panicle Counting</title>
      <link>/publications/deep_learning_count_panicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/deep_learning_count_panicles/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Small unmanned aerial systems (UAS) have emerged as high-throughput platforms for the collection of high-resolution image data over large crop fields to support precision agriculture and plant breeding research. At the same time, the improved efficiency in image capture is leading to massive datasets, which pose analysis challenges in providing needed phenotypic data.
To complement these high-throughput platforms, there is an increasing need in crop improvement to develop robust image analysis methods to analyze large amount of image data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian and Classical Machine Learning Methods: A Comparison for Tree Species Classification with LiDAR Waveform Signatures</title>
      <link>/publications/bayesian_machine_learning_new/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/bayesian_machine_learning_new/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
A plethora of information contained in full-waveform (FW) Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data offers prospects for characterizing vegetation structures.
Goal:
This study aims to investigate the capacity of FW LiDAR data alone for tree species identification through the integration of waveform metrics with machine learning methods and Bayesian inference.
Methods:
Specifically, we first conducted automatic tree segmentation based on the waveform-based canopy height model (CHM) using three approaches including TreeVaW, watershed algorithms and the combination of TreeVaW and watershed (TW) algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>waveformlidar: An R Package for Waveform LiDAR Processing and Analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/waveformlidar_r_package/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/waveformlidar_r_package/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
A wealth of FullWaveform (FW) LiDAR (Light Detection and Ranging) data are available to the public from different sources, which is poised to boost extensive applications of FW LiDAR data. However, we lack a handy and open source tool that can be used by potential users for processing and analyzing FW LiDAR data.
Goal: To this end, we introduce waveformlidar, an R package dedicated to FW LiDAR processing, analysis and visualization as a solution to the constraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating aboveground biomass and forest canopy cover with simulated ICESat-2 data</title>
      <link>/publications/icesat-2_biomass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/icesat-2_biomass/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
The Ice, Cloud and Land Elevation Satellite-2 (ICESat-2) launched on September 15th, 2018 and this mission offers an extraordinary opportunity to contribute to an assessment of forest resources at multiple spatial scales. This study served to develop a methodology for utilizing ICESat-2 data over vegetated areas.
Goal: The specific objectives were to: (1) derive a simulated ICESat-2 photon-counting lidar (PCL) vegetation product using airborne lidar data,
(2) examine the use of simulated PCL metrics for modelling aboveground biomass (AGB) along ICESat-2 profiles using a simulated ICESat-2 PCL vegetation product and reference AGB estimated from airborne lidar data, and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping forest aboveground biomass with a simulated ICESat-2 vegetation canopy product and Landsat data</title>
      <link>/publications/icesat-2_biomass_another/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/icesat-2_biomass_another/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: The assessment of forest aboveground biomass (AGB) can contribute to reducing uncertainties associated with the amount and distribution of terrestrial carbon. The Ice, Cloud and land Elevation Satellite-2 (ICESat-2) was launched on September 15th, 2018 and will provide data which will offer the possibility of assessing AGB and forest carbon at multiple spatial scales.
Goal: The primary goal of this study was to develop an approach for utilizing data similar to ICESat-2&amp;rsquo;s land-vegetation along track product (ATL08) to generate wall-to-wall AGB maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From LiDARWaveforms to Hyper Point Clouds: A Novel Data Product to Characterize Vegetation Structure</title>
      <link>/publications/hyper_point_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/hyper_point_cloud/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Full waveform (FW) LiDAR holds great potential for retrieving vegetation structure parameters at a high level of detail, but this prospect is constrained by practical factors such as the lack of available handy processing tools and the technical intricacy of waveform processing.
Methods:
This study introduces a new product named the Hyper Point Cloud (HPC), derived from FW LiDAR data, and explores its potential applications, such as tree crown delineation using the HPC-based intensity and percentile height (PH) surfaces, which shows promise as a solution to the constraints of using FW LiDAR data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photon counting LiDAR: An adaptive ground and canopy height retrieval algorithm for ICESat-2 data</title>
      <link>/publications/photon_couting_algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/photon_couting_algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
The upcoming Ice, Cloud and Land Elevation Satellite-2 (ICESat-2) mission will offer prospects for mapping and monitoring biomass and carbon of terrestrial ecosystems over large areas using photon counting LiDAR data
Goal:
We aim to develop a methodology to derive terrain elevation and vegetation canopy height from testbed sensor data and further pre-validate the capacity of the mission to meet its science objectives for the ecosystem community.
Methods:
We investigated a novel methodological framework with two essential steps for characterizing terrain and canopy height using Multiple Altimeter Beam Experimental LiDAR (MABEL) data and simulated ICESat-2 data with various vegetation conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting and Quantifying Standing Dead Tree Structural Loss with Reconstructed Tree Models Using Voxelized Terrestrial Lidar Data</title>
      <link>/publications/terrestrail_lidar_scan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/terrestrail_lidar_scan/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
The structural loss rates of standing dead trees (SDTs) affect a variety of processes of interest to ecologists and foresters, yet the decomposition of SDTs has been traditionally characterized by qualitative decay classes, reductions in wood density as decay progresses, and sampling schemes focused on estimating snag longevity.
By establishing a methodology to accurately and efficiently quantify SDT structural loss over time, these estimated structural loss rates would improve the performance of a variety of models and potentially provide new insight as to the manner in which SDTs undergo degradation in various conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian decomposition of full waveform LiDAR data with uncertainty analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/bayesian_decomposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/bayesian_decomposition/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
A thorough understanding of full waveform (FW) LiDAR data processing and associated uncertainty is critical to vegetation applications such as retrieving forest structure variables and estimating forest biomass.
Goal:
To qunaitfy the uncertaitny of the estimation and gain a deep understanding of waveform lidar processing.
Methods:
This paper applies the Bayesian non-linear modeling concept to process small-footprint FW LiDAR data (the Bayesian decomposition) collected at a study site of the National Ecological Observatory Network (NEON) to investigate its potential for waveform decomposition and uncertainty estimation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold-A novel deconvolution algorithm with optimization for waveform LiDAR processing</title>
      <link>/publications/gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/gold/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
Waveform Light Detection and Ranging (LiDAR) data have advantages over discrete-return LiDAR data inaccurately characterizing vegetation structure. However, we lack a comprehensive understanding ofwaveform data processing approaches under different topography and vegetation conditions.
Goal:
The objec-tive of this paper is to highlight a novel deconvolution algorithm, the Gold algorithm, for processingwaveform LiDAR data with optimal deconvolution parameters. Further, we present a comparative studyof waveform processing methods to provide insight into selecting an approach for a given combination ofvegetation and terrain characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>